A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Bettering the Health of Minority Americans, SG 2, Series 8 FA793
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Bettering the Health of Minority Americans, SG 2, Series 8
1988-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA793
14.81 Cubic Feet 39 letter document boxes.
Scope and Contents
Records primarily contain analysis and dissemination of the Minority Health Survey (Grant 95451), as well as the Women's Health Survey, and Women's Health Survey II, and development files for the Minority Health Chart Book. This series also documents the 1990s activities of Karen Scott Collins, and provides the 1990s presentation files of Karen Davis and Karen Scott Collins including presentations pertaining to women's health, minority health, and health care reform.
Arrangement
As received.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund records were donated to RAC in 1985. Record transfers began in 1986, and accruals continue.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
- Bettering the Health of Minority Americans, 1988-2000; 8; 14.81 Cubic Feet 39 letter document boxes
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Tabulations - Book I, 1994 August 17 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Tabulations - Book II, 1994 August 17 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Tabulations - Book III, 1994 August 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - African-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book II of III, 1994 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Asian Tabulations - Book I, 1994 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Asian Tabulations - Book II, 1994 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Asian Tabulations - Book II, 1994 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Asian-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book II of III, 1994 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Asian-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book III of III, 1994 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Latino Tabulations - Book I, 1994 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Latino Tabulations - Book II, 1994 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Latino Tabulations - Book III, 1994 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Latino Sample - Final Tabulations - Book I of III, 1994 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - Latino Sample - Final Tabulations - Book II of III, 1994 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - White Sample - Final Tabulations - Book I of III, 1994 September 1 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - White Sample - Final Tabulations - Book II of III, 1994 September 1 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Minority Health Survey (Study 932028) - White Sample - Final Tabulations - Book III of III, 1994 September 1 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Minority Health Survey - Minority Health Tabulations - Book I, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Minority Health Survey - Minority Health Tabulations - Book II, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Women's Health II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 3: Women - Health Care I, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Women's Health II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 1: Women - Demographics 1, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Women's Health II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 2: Women - Demographics 2, 1999 January (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls, 1998 June 29 (Fieldwork: 1996 September-1997 May) (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Minority Health Survey - African American Tabulations - Book I (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Minority Health Survey - Latino Sample - Final Tabulations - Book III of III (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Minority Health Survey - African American Tabulations - Book III (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Minority Health Survey - Final Tabulations - Book I of III (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Minority Health Survey - Final Tabulations - Book II of III (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Minority Health Survey - Final Tabulations - Book III of III (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Minority Health Survey - Asian-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book III (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Health Care Services and Minority Groups: A Comparative Survey of Whites, African-Americans, Hispanics and Asian-Americans, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Minority Health Survey - Latino Sample - Final Tabulations - Book I of III, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Minority Health Survey - Latino Sample - Final Tabulations - Book II of III, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Minority Health Survey - Latino Sample - Final Tabulations - Book III of III, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Minority Health Survey - African-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book I of III, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Minority Health Survey - African-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book II of III, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Minority Health Survey - African-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book III of III, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Background Information, Presentations and Articles, 1994-1998 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Minority Health Survey - White Sample - Final Tabulations - Book I of III, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Minority Health Survey - White Sample - Final Tabulations - Book II of III, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Minority Health Survey - White Sample - Final Tabulations - Book III of III, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Minority Health Survey - Asian-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book I of III, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Minority Health Survey - Asian-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book II of III, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Minority Health Survey - Asian-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book III of III, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Low Income and Access to Care - Preliminary Tabulations - Banner by Banner (Book 1 of 8), 1995 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Low Income and Access to Care - Preliminary Tabulations - Banner 1 (Book 2 of 8), 1995 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Low Income and Access to Care - Preliminary Tabulations - Banner 2 (Book 3 of 8), 1995 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Low Income and Access to Care - Preliminary Tabulations - Banner 4 (Book 5 of 8), 1995 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Health Care Services and Minority Groups: A Comparative Survey of Whites, African-Americans, Hispanics and Asian-Americans (Draft), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Minority Health Survey - African-American Tabulations - Book II, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Minority Health Survey - African-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book I of III, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Minority Health Survey - Asian-American Sample - Final Tabulations - Book I of III, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Minority Health Survey - Tabulations - Book III, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Low Income and Access to Care - 5 States: Final Tabulations - Banners 1 and 2, 1996 July 23 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Low Income and Access to Care - 5 States: Final Tabulations - Banners 3 and 4, 1996 July 23 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Low Income and Access to Care - 5 States: Final Tabulations - Banners 5 and 6, 1996 July 23 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Low Income and Access to Care - 5 States: Final Tabulations - Banner 7, 1996 July 23 (Box 15, Folder 59)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 1 - Women - Demographics 1, 1999 January (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 1 - Women - Demographics 2, 1999 January (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 3 - Women - Health Care 1, 1999 January (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 4 - Women - Health Insurance, 1999 January (Box 15, Folder 63)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 5 - Women - Violence, 1999 January (Box 16, Folder 64)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 6 - Women - Health Behaviors, 1999 January (Box 16, Folder 65)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 7 - Women - Health Care Utilization, 1999 January (Box 16, Folder 66)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner X Banner, 1999 January (Box 17, Folder 67-68)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 1 - Men - Demographics 1, 1999 January (Box 17, Folder 69)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 2 - Men - Demographics 2, 1999 January (Box 17, Folder 70)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 3 - Men - Health Care 1, 1999 January (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 4 - Men - Health Insurance, 1999 January (Box 18, Folder 72)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 5 - Men - Health Behaviors, 1999 January (Box 18, Folder 73)
  - Women's Health Survey II - Final Weighted Tabulations - Banner 6 - Men - Health Care Utilization, 1999 January (Box 18, Folder 74)
  - Harvard - Needleman (970645) - Preserving the Health Care Safety Net - Grant Products (Box 18, Folder 75)
  - Harvard - Needleman (970645) - Preserving the Health Care Safety Net - Grant Products (Box 19, Folder 76-78)
  - Harvard - Needleman (970645) - Preserving the Health Care Safety Net - Administration and Budget, 1997-2001 (Box 19, Folder 79)
  - Harvard - Needleman (970645) - Preserving the Health Care Safety Net - Proposal Development, Articles and Correspondence, 1997-2000 (Box 20, Folder 80)
  - Harvard - Needleman (970645) - Preserving the Health Care Safety Net (Box 20, Folder 81-83)
  - Harvard - Needleman (970645) - Preserving the Health Care Safety Net (Box 21, Folder 84)
  - NAPH - Needleman (96-004) (Box 21, Folder 85-86)
  - JFK School of Government - Zimmerman (990796) - Executive Program on Leadership in Minority Health, 1999-2000 (Box 21, Folder 87)
  - Association of Schools of Public Health - Gemmell (990774) - Minority Health Leadership Workshop (Box 21, Folder 88)
  - BHMA - Old Grants, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 89)
  - Grantmakers in Health - LeRoy (990563), 1999 (Box 22, Folder 90)
  - Program on Managed Care and Minority Health (990560) - Collins-Hall (Box 22, Folder 91)
  - Health Systems Research - Bartlett (990516) (Box 22, Folder 92)
  - Eisenberg-Harvard University (980909) - Thirty-Year Celebration of Affirmative Action (Box 22, Folder 93)
  - UCLA - Wenzel (980559) - Violence Against Homeless Women, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 94)
  - New York University (NYU) - Kaplan (980553) (Box 22, Folder 95)
  - Columbia University - Glied (980494) - Minority Health in a Changing Health Care System, 1998-1999 (Box 22, Folder 96)
  - George Washington University - Providers Serving Minority Communities in an Era of Managed Care (96175) - Administration and Articles (Box 22, Folder 97)
  - George Washington University - Zuvekas - Providers Serving Minority Communities in an Era of Managed Care (96175) - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 98)
  - George Washington University - Zuvekas - Providers Serving Minority Communities in an Era of Managed Care (96175) - Grant Products (Box 23, Folder 99-100)
  - Women's Health Program - 1993 Presentations - Health Care Reform (Box 23, Folder 101-103)
  - Women's Health Program - 1992 Presentations - Health Care Reform (Box 24, Folder 104-105)
  - Women's Health Program - Karen Scott Collins - Papers (Box 24, Folder 106)
  - Women's Health Program - Health Care Reform, 1992-1993 (Box 24, Folder 107-108)
  - Women's Health Program - Health Care Reform - Karen Davis Papers, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 109)
  - Women's Health Program - Health Care Reform - Karen Davis Conferences, 1993-1994 (Box 25, Folder 110-111)
  - Women's Health Program - Health Care Reform - Karen Scott Collins Presentations, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 112)
  - Women's Health Program - Health Care Reform - Speeches (Box 25, Folder 113)
  - Women's Health Program - Health Care Reform - Speeches, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 114)
  - APHA Meeting - Minority Health, 1997 November 9 (Box 26, Folder 115)
  - Presentations 1996 (Box 26, Folder 116-117)
  - Presentations 1996 (Box 27, Folder 118)
  - Presentations 1995 (Box 27, Folder 119-121)
  - Presentations 1994 (Box 27, Folder 122)
  - Presentations 1994 (Box 28, Folder 123-124)
  - Presentations 1993 (Box 28, Folder 125-127)
  - Assuring Quality, Information and Choice in Managed Care - Karen Davis Testimony before Congress, 1997 October 28 (Box 28, Folder 128)
  - Presentations 1998 (Box 28, Folder 129)
  - Presentations 1998 (Box 29, Folder 130-131)
  - Presentations 1999 (Box 29, Folder 132)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Agenda Management Meeting, 1996-1997 (Box 29, Folder 133)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Adolescent Girls Focus Group Report, 1996-1997 (Box 29, Folder 134)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Adolescent Girls Health Symposium, 1996-1997 (Box 29, Folder 135)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Communications Products, 1996-1997 (Box 29, Folder 136)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Advisory Committee Planning Schedule, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 137)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Commission on Women's Health (Box 30, Folder 138)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 139)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Child Care in the Context of Welfare Reform, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 140)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Georgetown Medical Center, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 141)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 30, Folder 142)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Grantmakers in Health, 1996-1997 (Box 30, Folder 143)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Harvard University Fellowship in Minority Health Policy, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 144)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Preserving the Health Care Safety Net, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 145)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation, 1996-1997 (Box 31, Folder 146-147)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Harvard Medical School, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 148)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Louis Harris and Associates, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 149)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Managed Care and Low Income Population, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 150)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Mathematica Policy Research Inc., 1996-1997 (Box 31, Folder 151)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Hedis 3.0, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 152)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Joint Center for Political and Economic Studies, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 153)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Medicaid, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 154)
  - Karen Scott Collins Chronological Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 32, Folder 155)
  - Karen Davis Presentations 1993 (Box 32, Folder 156)
  - Karen Davis Presentations 1994 (Box 32, Folder 157)
  - Health Care Reform Presentations, 1992-1993 (Box 33, Folder 158-159)
  - Health Care Reform Charts (Box 33, Folder 160-161)
  - Health Care Reform Charts (Box 34, Folder 162)
  - Presentations 1995 (Box 34, Folder 163)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Medicare, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 164)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Mental Health Symposium, 1995-1996 (Box 34, Folder 165)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Minority Health Survey, 1995-1996 (Box 34, Folder 166)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - National Committee for Quality Assurance (Box 34, Folder 167)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Phone Messages, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 168)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Picker-Commonwealth Fund Publications, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 169)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Proposals (Box 35, Folder 170)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Research Inventory of Managed Care for People with Disabilities, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 171)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Proposed Agenda for Board Meeting, 1997 April (Box 35, Folder 172)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Tracking Sheet, 1996-1997 (Box 35, Folder 173)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Uninsured, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 174)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - U.S.-Canada Paper Revisions, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 175)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Women for Health Education Reform and Equity (WHERE), 1997 (Box 35, Folder 176)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Women's Health Chart Book, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 177)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Research for Women's Health Conditions Discussion (Box 35, Folder 178)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Women's Research and Education Institute, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 179)
  - Karen Scott Collins Activities - Where It's @, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 180)
  - Presentations - Slides, 1990-1993 (Box 36, Folder 181-182)
  - Political Charts, 1988-1993 (Box 36, Folder 183)
  - Medicaid Charts, 1988-1993 (Box 36, Folder 184)
  - Physicians and Managed Care Survey Presentation, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 185)
  - Women's Health Presentations and Slides, 1990s (Box 36, Folder 186)
  - Women's Health Presentations and Slides, 1990s (Box 37, Folder 187)
  - Presentations 1996-1997 (Box 37, Folder 188)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Chapter 1 (Box 37, Folder 189-192)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Chapter 2 (Box 38, Folder 193-195)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Chapter 3 (Box 38, Folder 196-197)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Chapter 4 (Box 38, Folder 198)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Chapter 5 (Box 39, Folder 199)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Chapter 6 (Box 39, Folder 200)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Definitions (Box 39, Folder 201)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Appendix (Box 39, Folder 202)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Comments (Box 39, Folder 203)
  - Newsday Series, 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 204)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Charts (Box 39, Folder 205)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Outline (Box 39, Folder 206)
  - Minority Health Chart Book - Development - Literature Review (Box 39, Folder 207)